# **ROHITASH KATOR**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

rohitashkmwt@gmail.com

+91 9785787351

Jaipur, Rajasthan 333308

LinkedIn/GitHub/Portfolio

# Objective

A focused, energetic, and highly motivated software engineer with 1+ years of experience in software development with all levels of SDLC. I am seeking a Job in a reputed organization where I can utilize my excellent analytical, technical, and programming skills to help the organization produce high-quality software and web applications.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Associate Data Engineer at SpringML – Hyderabad, Telangana

July 2022 - Present

- Software & Web application development mainly in JavaScript, Angular, Python, and Flask
- ✓ Development & Integration of APIs mainly in Flask
- ✓ Participate in the development of Security assessment tools on GCP
- ✓ Google Associate Cloud Engineer certificate and GCP Knowledge from Google Cloud

# **INTERNSHIPS**

#### Consultant at iLink Digital – Pune, Maharashtra

January 2022 – April 2022

- ✓ Analytical and interactive visualization web application development mainly on Grafana using PostgreSQL and Elastic Search
- ✓ Development and Integration of APIs mainly using Python frameworks like Django and Flask

# ${\bf Software\ Developer\ at\ Jivrus\ Technologies} - \textit{Bengaluru,\ Karnataka}$

May 2021 – November 2021

- ✓ Web application development mainly in JavaScript, Node.js, and Angular
- ✓ Resolving issues and tickets raised by customers and clients
- ✓ Bug fixing and new features implementations

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Portfolio**

- ✓ A summary of a person that allows others to know about the educational and professional journey.
- ✓ Used Angular, Node.js, JavaScript/TypeScript.

#### Student Portal – Academic Project

- ✓ A full-stack web application to allow students to sign up and sign in
- Maintain a record of academic performance, attendance, and other curriculum activities
- ✓ Used JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, MySQL, HTML/CSS

#### To-Do App

- ✓ A full-stack web application to allow a user to manage daily tasks from a smartphone, tablet, or computer.
- ✓ Used JavaScript/TypeScript, Angular, HTML/CSS for client-side.
- ✓ Python, and Flask for server-side and Google Firebase for storage

#### **Crash Analytics**

- ✓ Web application to track crashes and analyses to get info about reasons behind road crashes, total, and average crashes in a year
- ✓ Used Angular, JavaScript/TypeScript, Flask, and its libraries.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Technology in CSE

National Institute of Technology, Andhra Pradesh

August 2018 – June 2022

#### **SKILLS**

- ➤ HTML/CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap
- JavaScript/TypeScript, Python
- > Angular, React, Node.js, Flask
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Git, GitHub, Google Cloud
- Data Structures and Algorithms

#### SOFT SKILLS

- ➤ Leadership
- > Time management
- ➤ Analytics and Problem-solving

# **LANGUAGES**

- ➤ Hindi Read, Write and Speak
- **English** Read, Write and Speak

#### **HOBBIES**

- ➤ Listening to soft music
- Playing Cricket and Badminton
- > Traveling and gardening

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- MongoDB Basics
- Associate Cloud Engineer
- > Python Programming
- MEAN Stack

# **VOLUNTEERING**

> Core Team Member

Developer Student Club at NIT Andhra Pradesh by Google Developers

Executive MemberE&I Cell at NIT Andhra Pradesh